Okay Katherine.
حسنًا كاثرين.
&gt;&gt; Mm-hm. &gt;&gt; So
&gt;&gt; حسنًا. &gt;&gt; وبالتالي
when we hit the plus button in that app.
عند الضغط على الزر + في التطبيق.
The number of cups of coffee goes up.
يزداد عدد أكواب القهوة لدينا.
&gt;&gt; Yeah it goes from two cups to three cups.
&gt;&gt; حسنا لقد ازداد من كوبين إلى ثلاثة أكواب.
And what happens when we press the plus button again?
وما الذي حدث عند الضغط على الزر + مرة أخرى؟
&gt;&gt; Well it actually just stays at three.
&gt;&gt; فقط استقر عند ثلاثة.
Yeah.
نعم.
So no matter how many times we press the plus button in that app,
ولذا بغض النظر عن عدد مرات الضغط على الزر + في هذا التطبيق
the number of cups of coffee stays at three.
يستقر عدد أكواب القهوة لدينا عند ثلاثة.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. &gt;&gt; Why is that happening?
&gt;&gt; نعم. &gt;&gt; لماذا يحدث ذلك؟
&gt;&gt; Well, I think it's because, in our code, we only update it to three.
&gt;&gt; حسنًا، أعتقد أن ذلك بسبب، في الكود، أننا نقوم بتحديثه إلى ثلاثة فقط.
And we never go beyond that.
ولم نذهب أبدًا بعيدًا عن ذلك.
&gt;&gt; Right. That number is hard coded right there.
&gt;&gt; حسنًا. وهذا الرقم يتعذر تغييره هناك.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. &gt;&gt; You know what this remind me of?
&gt;&gt; نعم. &gt;&gt; هل تعرف بما يذكرني؟
&gt;&gt; What is it?
&gt;&gt; ما هذا؟
&gt;&gt; Well, [LAUGH] my computer science professor in college used to say.
&gt;&gt; حسنًا، [LAUGH] يذكرني بقول أستاذ علوم الكمبيوتر في الكلية.
&gt;&gt; Yeah?
&gt;&gt; بالفعل؟
When you submit your final project.
عند إرسال المشروع النهائي.
&gt;&gt; Please, no magic numbers.
&gt;&gt; من فضلك، غير مسموح بالأرقام السحرية.
&gt;&gt; Wait, what's a magic number?
&gt;&gt; انتظر، ما الأرقام السحرية؟
&gt;&gt; Well, three's kind of a magic number.
&gt;&gt; حسنًا، هناك هذا نوع من الأرقام السحرية.
&gt;&gt; Okay. &gt;&gt; It's a magic number because,
&gt;&gt; حسنًا. &gt;&gt; هذا رقم سحري لأننا
we are doing the addition in our head, but then to the computer.
نحسب الإضافة في رأسنا، وبعد ذلك في الكمبيوتر.
&gt;&gt; We're telling it the right answer.
&gt;&gt; ونخبره الإجابة الصحيحة.
&gt;&gt; Okay, yeah, it would be better if the computer actually calculated itself.
&gt;&gt; حسنًا، سيكون من الأفضل إذا قام الكمبيوتر بالحساب بذاته.
&gt;&gt; Wait.
&gt;&gt; انتظر.
When you talk about calculation in math.
عند الحديث عن الحساب في الرياضيات
&gt;&gt; Uh-huh. &gt;&gt; I need to start writing things down.
&gt;&gt; اه ها. &gt;&gt; أنا بحاجة إلى تدوين بعض الأشياء.
&gt;&gt; Okay.
&gt;&gt; حسنًا.
Let's write some pseudocode.
هيا نكتب بعض الأكواد الصورية.
Let's write the pseudocode for this.
هيا نكتب الكود الصوري لهذا.
Assume that we've already created quantity variable and set it to two.
نفترض أننا قد أنشأنا متغير كمية بالفعل وتعيينه عند 2.
When the plus button in the app is pressed,
عند الضغط على الز + في التطبيق،
we're going to take the current quantity value which is two.
سنأخذ قيمة الكمية الحالية 2.
&gt;&gt; Add one to it to make it three, and
&gt;&gt; أضف 1 إليها كي تصبح 3،
then store that as the new value inside the quantity variable.
ثم تخزينها على أنها القيمة الجديدة داخل متغير الكمية.
If we hit the plus button again, then we're going to take the current
عند الضغط على الزر + مرة أخرى سنأخذ قيمة الكمية الحالية
quantity value which is now three, and add one to it which makes it four.
وهي 3، ونضيف عليها 1 كي تصبح 4.
And then store that as the new value inside the variable,
ثم تخزينها على أنها القيمة الجديدة داخل المتغير،
and here's the actual Java code for it.
وها هو كود جافا الفعلي لهذه القيمة.
We initialize a variable first.
نحن نقوم بتهيئة المتغير أولًا.
If the plus button is pressed again,
عند الضغط على الز + مرة أخرى،
then we're going to take the existing quantity value, add a one to it,
سنأخذ قيمة الكمية الموجودة، وإضافة 1 عليها
and then store this as the new value for the quantity variable.
ثم تخزينها على أنها القيمة الجديدة لمتغير الكمية.
When you read these lines of code, you can imagine the boxes in your head.
عند قراءة سطور الأكواد هذه، يمكنك تخيل المربعات في رأسك.
Even though we're used to reading things from left to right,
ورغم ذلك، لقد اعتدنا قراءة هذه الأشياء من اليسار إلى اليمين.
I always start with what's on the right hand side of the equal sign first.
دائمًا ما أبدأ مع القيمة الموجودة باليمين لعلامة يساوي.
In this case, we have the current value of quantity.
في هذه الحالة، لدينا قيمة الكمية الحالية.
Which is two, and then we add one to it, and that makes three.
وهي 2، ثم نضيف 1 إليها، كي تصبح 3.
Then we store the three inside the variable, like this.
ثم نخزن القيمة 3 داخل المتغير مثل ذلك.
The righthand side is an expression, which we learned about earlier.
الجانب الأيمن عبارة عن تعبير، قد تعلمنها في السابق.
And an expression can be made up variables, operators and
ويمكن إعداد تعبير للمتغيرات، والمعاملات
literal values, and more.
والقيم الحرفية وأكثر من ذلك.
If we click on the plus button again, then we can say quantity = quantity + 1.
عند النقر فوق الزر + مرة أخرى، بعد ذلك يمكن القول بأن الكمية = الكمية + 1.
At this point the current value of quantity is three,
في هذه الحالة، القيمة الحالية للكمية هي 3،
then we add one to it, and that makes four.
ثم نضيف 1 إليها، كي تصبح 4.
Then we store four as the new value inside the quantity variable like this.
ثم تخزين القيمة 4 على أنها القيمة الجديدة داخل متغير الكمية مثل هذا.
Essentially we've have reduced it down to a common pattern,
في الأساس لقد قمنا بتخفيضها إلى نمط مشترك،
that the computer can repeat each time the plus button is pressed.
حيث يتمكن الكمبيوتر من التكرار كل مرة يتم الضغط فيها على الزر +.
Instead of having to write a new line of code that says the explicit value of
وبدلًا من الاضطرار لكتابة سطر كود جديد يوفر القيمة الصريحة
the number of cups of coffee, we can just do quantity = quantity + 1,
لعدد أكواب القهوة، يمكننا فقط كتابة الكمية = الكمية + 1،
and continue to build off of the existing value of quantity.
والاستمرار في بناء قيمة الكمية الحالية.
This is a lot more flexible.
هذه الطريقة أكثر مرونة.
Say you You wanted to change initial quantity to 3,
ولذا أنت كنت تريد تغيير الكمية الأولية إلى 3،
then the rest of the lines of code wouldn't have to change at all.
وكان باقي سطور الكود غير مضطرة للتغيير على الإطلاق.
Because we would always use the latest value of quantity, whatever it is,
لأننا نرغب دائمًا في استخدام قيمة الكمية الأحدث، أيًا كانت،
which, in our old approach, if we wanted to update the quantity value to 3,
التي كانت في النهج القديم، إذا كنا نريد تحديث قيمة الكمية إلى 3،
then after you hit the plus button, you would have to write a new line of code
فقبل أن تضغط على الزر +، عليك كتابة سطر كود جديد
that says quantity equals 4 and update this to be quantity equals 5.
تقول فيه أن الكمية = 4 ثم التحديث لتصبح الكمية = 5.
When we update the quantity to a completely new literal value each time,
عند تحديث الكمية إلى قيمة حرفية جديدة تمامًا كل مرة،
it's hard for the computer to know what the pattern is between them.
فمن الصعب على الكمبيوتر معرفة النمط الذي يقع بينها.
Instead if we update quantity based on the current value of that variable and
وبدلًا من ذلك، عند تحديث الكمية حسب القيمة الحالية لهذا المتغير
we increment it in a predictable way, then the computer will be able to do
وقمنا بزيادته بطريقة يمكن التنبؤ بها، بعد ذلك يكون الكمبيوتر قادر على فعل ذلك
this every single time that the plus button is pressed.
في كل مرة يتم الضغط فيها على الزر +.
This approach will work a lot better for our coffee ordering app.
سيعمل هذا النهج بشكل أفضل بكثير في تطبيق طلب القهوة.
Each time we hit the plus button,
في كل مرة نضغط على الزر +،
we can just increase the existing quantity value by 1.
يمكننا فقط زيادة قيمة الكمية الموجودة بمعدل 1.
Practice writing out each line of code by typing them into the boxes we've
مارس كتابة كل سطر كود بالكتابة في هذه المربعات
provided here.
المقدمة لك.
Pay attention to each character and symbol.
ينبغي إيلاء اهتمام خاص لكل حرف ورمز.
This is the first time you're updating a variable, using the variable itself, so
هذه أول مرة تقوم فيها بتحديث متغير، باستخدام المتغير نفسه،
make sure you type out this variable name correctly.
لذا تأكد من كتابة اسم المتغير على نحوٍ صحيح.
When you're done, fill out this column that represents the current quantity
عند الانتهاء من ذلك، املأ هذا العمود الذي يمثل قيمة الكمية الحالية
value after each line of code is executed.
بعد تنفيذ سطر الكود.